{
  "adopted_lore_types": [
    "ARTIFACT",
    "CHARACTER",
    "CORPORATION",
    "COSMOLOGY",
    "FACTION",
    "GAME_SYSTEM",
    "INSTITUTION",
    "LOCATION",
    "LORE_EVENT",
    "MANUFACTURER",
    "MOON",
    "NARRATIVE",
    "ORGANIZATION",
    "PLANET",
    "QUEST",
    "REFERENCE",
    "REGION",
    "REGISTRY_AUDIT",
    "RESOURCE",
    "SECTOR",
    "SPECIES",
    "STAR_SYSTEM",
    "STATION",
    "TAXONOMY",
    "TECHNOLOGY",
    "WORLD"
  ],
  "authority": {
    "designation": "OPERATOR_DESIGNATED_CANONICAL_LORE_TAXONOMY_AND_NOMENCLATURE",
    "does_not_establish": [
      "ATMTA authorship or official publication status",
      "independent truth of every narrative claim",
      "governance, operational, provenance, or historical authority outside lore"
    ],
    "precedence": [
      "STAR_ATLAS_LORE_REPOSITORY_FOR_LORE_TAXONOMY_AND_PREFERRED_NAMES",
      "OFFICIAL_STAR_ATLAS_PUBLICATIONS_FOR_NEWER_LORE_NOT_YET_REPRESENTED",
      "ARCHIVE_HISTORICAL_SOURCES_FOR_HISTORICAL_EVIDENCE",
      "OPERATOR_CONFIRMATIONS_FOR_ARCHIVAL_AMBIGUITY",
      "DERIVED_KNOWLEDGE_FOR_DISCOVERY_ONLY"
    ],
    "scope": "IN_UNIVERSE_LORE_ONLY"
  },
  "compatibility_limitations": {
    "ARTIFACT": "Repository Schema v2.1 has no ARTIFACT type; RESOURCE is retained as the broad compatibility type and lore_type=ARTIFACT is authoritative.",
    "SPECIES": "Repository Schema v2.1 has no SPECIES type; COMMUNITY is retained as the broad compatibility type and lore_type=SPECIES is authoritative.",
    "place_subtypes": "PLANET, WORLD, MOON, STATION, STAR_SYSTEM, SECTOR, and REGION refine Repository Schema v2.1 LOCATION."
  },
  "entity_counts": {
    "ARTIFACT": 3982,
    "CHARACTER": 311,
    "COSMOLOGY": 1,
    "FACTION": 86,
    "GAME_SYSTEM": 1,
    "INSTITUTION": 2,
    "LOCATION": 18,
    "LORE_EVENT": 4,
    "MANUFACTURER": 3,
    "NARRATIVE": 1,
    "PLANET": 32,
    "QUEST": 1,
    "REFERENCE": 9,
    "REGION": 5,
    "REGISTRY_AUDIT": 5,
    "RESOURCE": 93,
    "SECTOR": 53,
    "SPECIES": 9,
    "STAR_SYSTEM": 4,
    "STATION": 1,
    "TAXONOMY": 3,
    "TECHNOLOGY": 1,
    "WORLD": 7
  },
  "hierarchy": {
    "AGENT": [
      "CHARACTER",
      "SPECIES",
      "FACTION",
      "ORGANIZATION",
      "INSTITUTION",
      "CORPORATION",
      "MANUFACTURER"
    ],
    "CONCEPT": [
      "TECHNOLOGY",
      "GAME_SYSTEM",
      "COSMOLOGY"
    ],
    "DOCUMENTARY": [
      "NARRATIVE",
      "QUEST",
      "TAXONOMY",
      "REFERENCE",
      "REGISTRY_AUDIT"
    ],
    "OBJECT": [
      "ARTIFACT",
      "RESOURCE"
    ],
    "OCCURRENCE": [
      "LORE_EVENT"
    ],
    "PLACE": [
      "REGION",
      "SECTOR",
      "STAR_SYSTEM",
      "WORLD",
      "PLANET",
      "MOON",
      "STATION",
      "LOCATION"
    ]
  },
  "identifier_policy": "LRTX identifiers are deterministic source-taxonomy IDs and do not replace registry-assigned repository canonical IDs.",
  "repository_schema_compatibility": {
    "ARTIFACT": "RESOURCE",
    "CHARACTER": "PERSON",
    "CORPORATION": "CORPORATION",
    "COSMOLOGY": "DOCUMENT",
    "FACTION": "ORGANIZATION",
    "GAME_SYSTEM": "GAME_SYSTEM",
    "INSTITUTION": "ORGANIZATION",
    "LOCATION": "LOCATION",
    "LORE_EVENT": "EVENT",
    "MANUFACTURER": "CORPORATION",
    "MOON": "LOCATION",
    "NARRATIVE": "DOCUMENT",
    "ORGANIZATION": "ORGANIZATION",
    "PLANET": "LOCATION",
    "QUEST": "DOCUMENT",
    "REFERENCE": "DOCUMENT",
    "REGION": "LOCATION",
    "REGISTRY_AUDIT": "DOCUMENT",
    "RESOURCE": "RESOURCE",
    "SECTOR": "LOCATION",
    "SPECIES": "COMMUNITY",
    "STAR_SYSTEM": "LOCATION",
    "STATION": "LOCATION",
    "TAXONOMY": "DOCUMENT",
    "TECHNOLOGY": "TECHNOLOGY",
    "WORLD": "LOCATION"
  },
  "taxonomy_id": "STAR-ATLAS-LORE-TAXONOMY-22555F2",
  "version_basis": "22555f277eb1496e34c0839c8f1f382842bd1d2b"
}
